

Long, Thay Bun

Fullstack Developer

Email: thaybunlong20@gmail.com

Cell: +84-9-88-99-7071

Github: https://github.com/foxbunlong

Summary

Professional Experience: Software engineering, Automation and Integration (CI/CD), Mobile development, UI/UX analyst, Database analyst, Workflow analyst

Specialties

Software Engineer, CI/CD, Shell script Development, Mobile Development, UI/UX Analyst, Server Architecture, Networking, Database Architecture, Dataflow designing and managing

Experience

Senior Fullstack Developer at Hung Thai Technology (April 2022 - Present)

Duties:

- Develop mobile platform for Livin PMH app (Static map, Google Map, Animation)
- Develop front end admin (Backoffice) to control mobile app contents (NextJS)
- Propose solution to authenticate new user (OAuth, ReCaptcha V2)
- Implement new api for backend tasks (NestJS)

Senior Mobile Engineer at Neo Consulting (September 2021 - April 2022)

Duties:

- Managing app for different clients (different environments and api configurations)
- Implement CI/CD and Automation for business process
- Mobile team management (8 members)
- Contact point for backend and integration
- Contact point for business process change

Senior Software Engineer (Former Product/Project Manager) at Concung.com (August

2016 - May 2021 (4 years 9 months))

Duties:

Senior Software Engineer and Former Product/Project Manager for Internal ERP system and e-commerce

- Build Android Native app
- Use MVP and MVC for 2 projects
- Google Maps, Google Analytics integrated

- Implementing consistent backend and mobile app
- Guarantee the highest quality app
- Build socket service for Android apps
- Deploy NodeJS and Socket IO for social network module
- Product development for e-commerce app (features, functions and business flow)
- Lead team to research and make app using Flutter (Moon Sheep project Moon & Sheep: Ngủ Ngon - Apps on Google Play

And Concung e-commerce Con Cung - Tã Sữa Khuyến Mãi - Apps on Google Play)

Technical Project Manager at Pakme (March 2017 - November 2018 (1 year 8 months)) Duties:

PAKME project - Park car in city participated in SharkTank Vietnam Former/Part-time project manager for PAKME project.

- Implementing backend using NodeJS
- Revamping mobile app (Android and iOS)
- Consulting on feature, design and payment options
- Recruit development team
- Manage project life cycle using Scrum

Technical Leader at FPT Telecom (September 2015 - July 2016 (10 months)) Duties:

- Build Android app for 2 applications: ABC Play and ABC Play TV
- Involving in product development for video streaming app (Kid lock, timing)
- Developing deep links, remote control and cast feature for FPT Play
- Lead a iOS developer to create ABC Play app for Android and iOS.
- Lead a sub project for Mobifone (Biboplay project)
- Scrum master for full product life cycle
- Main contact point between mobile developers and other team (python, design, content and marketing...

Android Developer at Officience (October 2014 - August 2015 (10 months))

Duties:

- Android developer for many outsourcing project
- Apply Scrum Agile for development process

Android Developer at Audience Media (November 2012 - July 2014 (1 year 9 months)) Duties:

Android coding

- Git server deployment
- Jenkins deployment (Setup Jenkins on Linux server)
- In-app purchasing (Google Play payment)
- Braintree in-app purchase
- Apply Google Maps API for Android

IT and Database Specialist at Therm-x SVT (July 2010 - July 2011 (1 year 1 month)) Duties:

- IT Expert to maintain network and PC performance
- Input data for company's website

Leader of Orientation team - Go Google Project at RMIT International University Vietnam (September 2008 - November 2008 (3 months)) Duties:

• RMIT's email system was migrated from Microsoft Exchange to Google Mail service for education. The transformation was huge and time budget was critical. We were successful in testing new service and decided to deploy new system within semester 3-2011. Orientation team included 34 students from Saigon South campus and 6 from Hanoi campus. I had been assigned as leader of Saigon South campus's Orientation team to provide instruction to students who are not familiar with Gmail and other Google Apps. This experience strengthened my tele-communication and management skills to advanced level.

Projects

Livin PMH (Hung Thai Technology)

Senior Fullstack Developer - April 2022 - Present

Phu My Hung residence service app

Technology: React Native, Expo, NextJS (Theme with Ant Design), Tiny Editor, NestJs (API),

Shell Script, Captcha V2, Google Maps for RN, Custom deeplink, Mixpanel, Docker.

Sport apps (Neo Consulting)

Senior Mobile Engineer - September 2021 - April 2022

Sport Mobile app for Malaysia market

Technology: Shell script, Fastlane, Gitlab CI, Kotlin native Android app, NDK support for security improvement, custom deeplink, applink, custom Webview, Facebook sdk, Firebase FCM, Firebase Crashlytic sdk.

Concung ERP and Concung E-commerce

Senior Software Engineer - August 2018 - May 2021 Internal ERP mobile app and e-commerce mobile app

Project homepage: https://www.concung.com

Technology: ERP system, e-commerce platform, Google maps sdk, shopping cart, content distribution, Kotlin native Android app, NDK support for security improvement, custom deeplink, applink, custom Webview, Facebook sdk, Firebase FCM, Firebase Crashlytic sdk.

PAKME

Part-time Project Manager - March 2017 - November 2017

Parking mobile app (Startup company)

Project homepage: pakme.co

Technology: Maps, realtime, location based

ABC Play - Android TV

Technical leader & Senior Android Developer - January 2016 - July 2016

Video streaming application for kid. Customized for Android TV

Project homepage: https://fptplay.tv

Technology: Android TV / UI / Leanback / Remote control, Java native Android app, NDK

support for security improvement.

ABC Play - Android

Technical leader & Senior Android Developer - October 2015 - July 2016

Video streaming application for kid

Project homepage: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=vn.abcplay.app.full

Technology: Android Custom Exoplayer, Java native Android app, NDK support for security improvement.

BiboPlay - Android

Technical leader & Senior Android Developer - February 2016 - April 2016

Mobifone owned Video streaming application for kid

Project homepage:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=vn.com.mobifoneplus.app.biboplay.full

Technology: Android Custom Exoplayer, Java native Android app, NDK support for security improvement.

FPT Play - Android

Senior Android Developer - September 2015 - November 2015

Video streaming application

Project homepage: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fplay.activity

Technology: Android Custom Exoplayer, Google Cast / ConnectSDK, Deeplink

Mocto Graphy

Senior Android Developer - May 2015 to Present

Selfie application

Project homepage:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.foxgroupvietnam.selfiewithmeomoc&hl=en

Technology: Android CameraV1

Chuyen Hang Ngay

Senior Android Developer - December 2012 to Present

Local news app for Android

Project homepage:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.foxgroupvietnam.chuyenhangngay&hl=en

Technology: Android Custom Webview, Custom Fragment Controller, Youtube API

Simple Cell Wallpaper

Senior Android Developer - November 2014 to Present

Android widget app to change background of Android home

Project homepage:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.foxgroupvietnam.simplewallpaper&hl=en

Technology: Android Custom Gridview, Color blending

Vietnam Korean Magazine (VKTimes) for Android

Android Developer - March 2013 to July 2014

News and magazine application for English, Korean and Vietnamese habitats

Technology: Android Custom Webview, Google Maps api for Android

CIO India

Android Developer - December 2012 to July 2014
News and magazine application of CIO East Africa

Technology: Android Custom Webview, Custom Viewpager, Custom Indicator

Brainwave Magazine

Android Developer - February 2013 to July 2014
News and magazine application of Brainwave

Technology: Android Custom Webview, Custom Viewpager, Custom Indicator

National Geographic Channel India

Android Developer - March 2013 to July 2014

News and magazine application of National Geographic Channel India

Technology: Android Custom Webview, Custom Viewpager, Custom Indicator

workin'SFR Project

Software Engineer - August 2014 to April 2015

An internal used Android software for Human resource solution for Android users

Technology: Native C, NDK development, Streaming videos

CleanAir

Software Engineer - November 2014 to January 2015

A internal used Android software for Service ordering and customer support

Technology: Native C, NDK development, Streaming videos

Skills & Expertise

Android / Java / Kotlin

Android TV / UI / Leanback / Remote control

Android Google Cast / ConnectSDK

Android Deeplink

Android Custom Exoplayer

Fastlane / Gitlab CI

Custom Adapter for Listview, Viewpager, Gridview and Gallery

SQLite Database for Android

Google Maps API for Android

Google In-App Billing for Android

Google Ad Planner for Android

Google Maps for Android

Networking Framework for Android

iOS / Objective-C

Git

SVN

Version Control Management Branching

Web Service Development

Web Services API

Business Analysis

Server Architecture

Microsoft SQL Server

VB.NET

Databases

Networking (Cisco)

Shell script / Terminal (mac os, linux)

Android Development

PHP

MySQL

Remote User Support

Web Applications

XHTML

Software Development

Subversion

Web Development

NestJS

NextJS

Docker

Education

RMIT Vietnam University

Bachelor, Business Information Systems, 2008 - 2011

SaigonCTT

CCNA preparation program

Ho Chi Minh city University of Science

iOS Development

Honors and Awards

Active member of Ubuntu forum

Interests

Technology, Computer, Network, Internet, Online game, PC game, Open source software, Shareware